ANDRAS NEMESERI

PROFILE

I am a detail-oriented full-stack software engineer with over 15 years of professional experience, specializing in front-end development. During this time, I have delivered numerous complex websites and applications, and led teams as a Product Architect.

For the past 10 years, I have focused on building multilingual enterprise web applications.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR FRONT-END ENGINEER, IBM ENGINEERING LIFECYCLE MANAGEMENT; SAN FRANCISCO, CA – 2022-PRESENT

Currently, I work on the Requirements Management and Report Builder applications in our ELM software suite. My primary focus is on redesigning and redeveloping our existing applications using React and the Carbon Design System, while also adding new features and maintaining the older versions of these products.

SENIOR FRONT-END ENGINEER, IBM VIDEO STREAMING; SAN FRANCISCO, CA – 2016-2022

After IBM acquired Ustream, our video streaming product transitioned from a consumer-facing platform to a SaaS enterprise solution. I worked on integrating our products into IBM's ecosystem, developing new dashboard features, and redesigning our legacy pages in React and the Carbon Design System. Collaborated daily with product, marketing, sales, and customer success teams while providing support to key customers.

SENIOR FRONT-END ENGINEER, USTREAM.TV; SAN FRANCISCO, CA – 2012-2016 I joined Ustream's San Francisco-based team to collaborate closely with the product, marketing, sales, and customer success teams, while leading our local developer team. I was also responsible for designing and developing MVPs for the sales engineering team and working on custom projects for our largest customers.

FRONT-END ENGINEER, USTREAM.TV; BUDAPEST, HUNGARY – 2010-2012 Completed multiple site-wide redesign projects and core product pages. As a Product Architect, I coordinated and led the development of our Facebook App and Open Graph integration. In 2010, I was rewarded with the Employee of the Year award.

FRONT-END DEVELOPER, CARNATION; BUDAPEST, HUNGARY - 2008-2010

Built numerous web portals, newsletters, landing pages, and micro-sites. Successfully delivered projects for companies with the highest standards, including Procter & Gamble, E.ON, Telenor, Tesco, and Ringier.

FULL STACK ENGINEER, NETRIX; BUDAPEST, HUNGARY - 2006-2008

Developed and maintained high-traffic websites based on the company's proprietary CMS. Designed and developed new modules within the existing CMS and established front-end coding standards for the company.

FULL STACK ENGINEER, AKAKIKO; GYOR, HUNGARY - 2005-2006

Developed the website's online credit card payment system, and designed and developed multiple internal web applications for monitoring orders, scheduling shifts, and exporting and analyzing order data.

EDUCATION

SZECHENYI ISTVAN UNIVERSITY, GYOR, HUNGARY

BSC - ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING / TELECOMMUNICATIONS-INFORMATICS

SKILLS

- 15+ years of Javascript experience (ES6+)
- 5 years of experience in React and related technologies (Next.js, React Query, Redux...)
- 3 years of TypeScript experience
- UI frameworks (Carbon, Radix, MUI)
- Experience working with REST APIs
- Styling languages and libraries (CSS3, SASS/SCSS, Tailwind, Bootstrap)
- Markup languages (HTML5, XHTML, XML)
- Node.js and PHP backend skills
- Testing using Vitest and Playwright
- Legacy Javascript frameworks (e.g., ¡Query, Dojo)
- Database design (PostgreSQL, MySQL)
- Web development patterns (MVC, MVW, MicroServices, Mobile First)
- Agile methodologies (Scrum, Kanban)
- Source code management and version control systems (GIT, SVN)
- Design and prototyping tools (Sketch, Figma, InVision, Adobe Suite)
- Collaboration tools (JIRA, Confluence, Slack, Box etc.)
- Data privacy concepts (GDPR)
- Proficient in using and configuring UNIX-based systems (macOS, Linux)

Special interest in web performance, usability, UI/UX, accessibility, and product design.